<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WillPopScope on FlutterrettulF | Learn Flutter | Android Mobile Development | iOS Mobile Development</title>
    <link>https://flutterrettulf.com/tags/willpopscope/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WillPopScope on FlutterrettulF | Learn Flutter | Android Mobile Development | iOS Mobile Development</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flutterrettulf.com/tags/willpopscope/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to disable the backbutton in Flutter using WillPopScope.</title>
      <link>https://flutterrettulf.com/navigation/2022/09/03/how-to-disable-backbutton-in-flutter-using-willpopscope.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flutterrettulf.com/navigation/2022/09/03/how-to-disable-backbutton-in-flutter-using-willpopscope.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction WillPopScope class in Flutter is used to create a Widget that registers a callback to veto attempts by the user to dismiss the enclosing ModalRoute. This is useful when you want to prevent the user from accidentally exiting the app or navigating back to the previous screen.
If you want to know more about the WillPopScope widget, you can read the article How to use the WillPopScope widget in Flutter In this article, we will see how to disable the backbutton in Flutter using the WillPopScope widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use WillPopScope widget in Flutter with examples.</title>
      <link>https://flutterrettulf.com/navigation/2022/09/03/how-to-use-willpopscope-widget-in-flutter-with-examples.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flutterrettulf.com/navigation/2022/09/03/how-to-use-willpopscope-widget-in-flutter-with-examples.html</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will discuss how to use the WillPopScope class in Flutter.
What is WillPopScope? WillPopScope class in Flutter is used to create a Widget that registers a callback to veto attempts by the user to dismiss the enclosing ModalRoute. In other words, it can be used to override what happens when a user presses the back button on the device or pops the current route.
The constructor of the class is as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use the WillPopScope widget in Flutter to show Press Back Button Again to Exit App?</title>
      <link>https://flutterrettulf.com/navigation/2022/09/03/press-back-button-again-to-exit-app-flutter-willpopscope-widget.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flutterrettulf.com/navigation/2022/09/03/press-back-button-again-to-exit-app-flutter-willpopscope-widget.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss how to use the WillPopScope widget in Flutter to show a snackbar saying press back button again to exit app. If you are not familiar with the WillPopScope widget, you can read the article How to use the WillPopScope widget in Flutter In order to exit the app, we need to press the back button twice. The first time we press the back button, we will show a snackbar saying press back button again to exit app.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
